<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Ben Slater]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Ben Slater]]></description>
        <link>https://thegrid.ai/benslater/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 09:56:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://thegrid.ai/benslater/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NAAMYAA – East West Conversations]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>NAAMYAA – East West Conversations</h1><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/564e95d45367d4b2d5d1683ea1505543a60cab25.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/benslater/naamyaa-east-west-conversations/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">329561ad-cf95-444e-b51b-a25984dbbd58</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 09:44:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Can you briefly explain the work you do?North: I work as a Graphic Designer and Illustrator. I work over a wide range of communication design from logos and branding, to packaging design and editorial illustrations. I frequently contribute to Aarn Journal (simply translated to Read Journal) which focuses on politics, cultural and current affairs. Between working from my studio on personal and commissioned work, I also tutor Graphic Design at Bangkok University.Ben: I’m also a graphic designer but I’m also an art director, which includes magazine design, branding, web design, concept creation and visual communication. I’m also working in the area of User Interface design, working on some touch screen apps. I have a background in architecture, so I love to mix a bit of 3D work into projects if the opportunity arises.•How do you feel the cities you live in influence your work?N: I started my career in NY and from that experience I learnt two key things:
1. I think people drive creativity by positive feelings and I’ve learnt that being generous is key. There are always ways to say things nicer and talking negatively to others is simply careless.
2. Your work says a lot about who you are and how you like to work.B: For me it’s also two things, the diversity and also the sheer size of London. Diversity creates an array of ideas, perspectives and viewpoints that keep your eyes open that little bit wider.

Also the sheer mass of buildings and streets in London for me is a constant source of excitement. I love how you can walk down a different street every day if you want, and often it’s nice just to do this, even if there is a slight risk of getting lost, just to discover a quirky piece of graffiti, a random park or sculpture.•North, What made you return to your hometown, Bangkok (BKK)?N: The main reason was family, and secondly I wanted to try to focus on setting up my own design studio which is still quite new, but exciting to be building up my own creative practice.•In terms of culture, NY & BKK differ quite a lot but would you say they also shared certain traits?
N: There are many statuses in BKK that will make people respect you, such as age, education and family, etc… But in NY this is less important, people respect by who you are and your quality of work.
•What do you think is the biggest difference between Bangkok and NY?
N: In BKK, I see many designers make their appearance in public but I see little design work. In NYC, I see more work but only few designers appear in public. This, along with working and communicating in Thai; it helps the clarity of my work and creativity; to express myself to clients and colleagues, getting the best out of myself and the work my studio produces.

•What are your views on graphic design in Thailand and Asia?N: I don’t really have ideas about graphic design in Asia as it’s such a diverse continent, but in Thailand I wish I could see more variety in this field. There isn’t a huge platform for different creative directions but this isn’t necessarily bad, it means there are plenty of empty places to explore.•Ok, which direction would you like Bangkok to progress in? 
N: Wider, and with more variety to be open. Maybe this is not a question only for designers but also for consumers and the market too. I can however see change, there’s an emerging culture of vibrant designers and artists, which encourages new consumers and brings a circle of positive change. There seems to be more and more people who are aware and interested in the creative culture based in BKK.•Ben, You’ve spent all your working life in London. How did your career start out and how has your early experience influenced the way you work now? 
B: If I take you back to the start, the spark came from collecting flyers from club nights and music events and also looking at music and lifestyle magazines. I seemed to get inspired by what other people were doing and how they affected me and the people around me in positive ways, and that inspired me into thinking how I could do this as well.
I think the initial excitement that came from experiencing these designs still follows through in what I do now, just I guess my eye is more finely tuned, I’m much less easily pleased and tastes have developed.•What excites you most about your hometowns?N: 1. Contrast. Bangkok is the city that blends things from different sides. Expensive food or cheap street food can both be equally as enjoyable.
2. People’s opinions. Sometimes, people here are so worried about nonsenses. At the same time they can ignore the very important things that will influence their whole life.B: I’ve always found London is a melting pot of ideas, with so many passionate creatives pushing hard to go their own way. There is also a big excitement and energy around the scene, mixed with a very healthy strong work ethic – which I think partly is essential due to the toughness of London and necessity to swim rather than sink.•From where do you take your inspirations?
N: Learning from masters, architecture, fine arts, music and meeting people.B: For me it’s all about having a good dose of diverse / interesting experiences every day, and meeting new people. I think if you have a passion for what you do then, I find, the projects and designs you’re working on are always in the back of your head, so during the time you have outside the ‘creative’ hours your brain makes natural links and the next time you sit down, inspiration occurs. Also exercise is a big thing for me now (it wasn’t always), but I find it mixes up things for a small amount of time, and usually ideas can come to you when you are sweaty and out of breath!•What is your ultimate Saturday or Sunday in BKK?N: Having a good brunch with my wife and my son, or to have dinner with my mom and laugh. When my son says he wants Hom Hom (‘Smells Good’) we know he wants a particular noodle shop close to our house.B: I wouldn’t mind what it was, as long as it’s something I’ve never done before, preferably with people that are also interested in experiencing new things!•Which brings us onto your favourite local spots to eat! Where are they?
N: From my house you can cycle for about 10 minutes and you can get to Senaniwet where there are so many noodle shops to choose from. I’m sure all the local households have fun trying all the different stalls. There are many famous noodle stalls and eateries but I tend to prefer the smaller places. Two of my favourite dishes are grilled meatballs that you dip in really spicy or sweet chilli sauce; and from another noodle stall close by I like the fried Lad Naa (Cantonese Ho Fun).
One thing I’ve learnt is that there’s always a better noodle shop than the one you’ve just had!

B: My favourite places are: Young Cheng, Shaftesbury Avenue – for first class, down to earth, authentic Chinese food (I’m half Chinese so it’s good to connect with my roots!)
Buen Ayre on Broadway Market – for an unrivalled Argentine grill meat feast
Honest Burgers in Brixton – for a brilliant burger, surrounded by the life and energy of the up-and-coming Brixton village (also voted best burgers in London!)
And Karnaphuli Restaurant, Church Street – for an original and first class Indian culinary adventure.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/benslater/5fcfdd0b-36a2-4122-9849-e5a6e19c0248/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">5fcfdd0b-36a2-4122-9849-e5a6e19c0248</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 09:34:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>At Naamyaa we love meeting people, especially when they’re happy to offer us a glimpse into their work and past times, and even more so when they live in parallel cultures! Each issue we will chat with two professionals around the world and explore how the lives of two contemporaries differ depending on which part of the world they’re in. This issue we meet two graphic designers; one based in London and one in Bangkok, both united by their love of shapes colours and lines.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/benslater/317d8227-cde0-478f-8c08-ed6b1c6678bf/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">317d8227-cde0-478f-8c08-ed6b1c6678bf</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 08:14:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/f1df2bb8-2130-4b06-b9fc-6f7ddc40a42d.jpg">]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/benslater/783c8c68-27e9-4eeb-8a47-360cafd1d782/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">783c8c68-27e9-4eeb-8a47-360cafd1d782</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 21:30:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Ben is the founding Art Director for the award winning Glass Magazine - an international publication based around fashion, culture and the arts. Glass recently celebrated its 5th birthday, a seminal moment at the forefront of honest, sustainable journalism and design. He currently also holds the position of Art Director for WeTheUrban Magazine, a cutting edge viral Tumblr magazine led by one of the youngest Editor-in-Chiefs in history, the spirited Willie Greene.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/benslater/c4c13c30-123f-452a-a15c-3e7a262e9d74/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">c4c13c30-123f-452a-a15c-3e7a262e9d74</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 09:55:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>